<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>{{ name: Shain Singh }}</title>
    <link>https://oi.shain.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on {{ name: Shain Singh }}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oi.shain.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>$ linux on macos</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/linux-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/linux-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>I bought my first Apple laptop in 2005 as I was keen to leverage native UNIX programs on x86 hardware. Since that time there have a number of packaging managers that I have used (Fink, Macports) to now settle on Homebrew for installing UNIX programs on my laptop.
In recent years I have found that even with a package manager, software libraries and dependencies of non-native versions of Python and Ruby make installation of programs quite bloated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/presentations/</guid>
      <description>2022 September
Australian Network Operators Groups (AusNOG) - AusNOG 2022: slides: SaaS-Based Operations - Distributed Infrastructure and POP Management June
BrightTALK Webinar: slides: OWASP Top 2021 - The New Risk Order video: https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/17570/550335 April
BrightTALK Webinar: slides: Towards a Zero Trust Architecture video: https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/17570/540251 March
Philippine Institute of Cybersecurity Professionals (PICSPro): slides: Insights from 2022 Application Protection Report video: https://www.facebook.com/PICSProfessionals/videos/685974415881142 2021 November
Australian Information Security Association (AISA) - Australian Cyber Conference 2021:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ the three most important api specs i see at work</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/the-three-most-important-api-specs-i-see-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/the-three-most-important-api-specs-i-see-at-work/</guid>
      <description>One of the most rewarding things about my role at F5 is that it involves talking to customers about their digital transformation initiatives. The benefit of working for a company that provides a gateway, web application and API protection and fraud/automated threat defence means that my conversations and workshops are never boring!
Through my customers I have learnt about how APIs have become a critical piece of infrastructure. My real sense of satisfaction comes not only when I help them plug any security gaps they may have, but when I combine with my partner-in-crime Shahnawaz Backer to provide them with threat data and insights (something they don&amp;rsquo;t need to wait to read in front page news).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ my life through sound</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/my-life-through-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/my-life-through-sound/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Sound&amp;rdquo; as the word &amp;ldquo;music&amp;rdquo; attaches a personal taste, a subjective view, a reason to judge. Throughout my life songs have been able to put me back into a place, a time. I am not alone when I say that I can resort to music during my happiest, darkest or most sombre moments. My love for music has seen me keep vinyl/cassette collections, which turned into CD collections, which moved to iTunes mp3 playlists and now a curated streaming collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ thoughts on zoom</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/thoughts-on-zoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/thoughts-on-zoom/</guid>
      <description>The past few months have placed immense demand on remote working and particularly video-conferencing tools. This has placed greater scrutiny on the security practices of companies like Zoom which has received a great deal of press - resulting in better transparency and a commitment to its users for improving its controls.
Putting opinions and conjecture aside for a moment, Zoom&amp;rsquo;s current posture and response got me thinking - in particular, the following aspects were of interest to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ init</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/init/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/init/</guid>
      <description>A new tech blog sees the light of day. As if there weren’t enough of them already&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/training/</guid>
      <description>SSL Orchestrator The following document accompanies the SSL Orchestrator Lab.
Author: F5
Presenter: Shain Singh
SSL Orchestrator 9.1 Lab Guide - supplement to instructor-led lab DevSecOps Presentation given to F5 Networks partners as part of a Security workshop (including a Capture The Flag tournament). Dockerfile for DevSecOps pipeline demo can be found here: https://github.com/F5-use-cases/f5-rs-container
Author: F5
Presenter: Shain Singh
Security in a Agile/DevOps environment DevSecOps Demo with Jenkins DDoS The following documents are recommendations from F5 around how best to prepare and mitigate against DDoS attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/about/</guid>
      <description>$ POST /about?definition=blog पुरुषार्थ (puruṣārtha)- the Hindu belief that there are four goals or objectives for human existence.
Kāma: sensory pleasure Artha: material prosperity Dharma: moral righteousness Mokṣa: spiritual liberation My aim will be to cover materials painted in the colours of the four goals of puruṣārtha.
Enjoy your visit.
नमस्ते (Namaste)
$ GET /info?id=shsingh Bio I know stuff about things, or things about stuff&amp;hellip; At least I try to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ research</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/research/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe&amp;#34; - Abraham Lincoln I am still learning how exactly to use this medium to write. The lack of content for a while is not indicative of an absence of posts to publish, rather a “getting to know one’s surrounds”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
