<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>{{ name: Shain Singh }}</title>
    <link>https://oi.shain.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on {{ name: Shain Singh }}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oi.shain.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>$ my life through sound</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/my-life-through-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/my-life-through-sound/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Sound&amp;rdquo; as the word &amp;ldquo;music&amp;rdquo; attaches a personal taste, a subjective view, a reason to judge. Throughout my life songs have been able to put me back into a place, a time. I am not alone when I say that I can resort to music during my happiest, darkest or most sombre moments. My love for music has seen me keep vinyl/cassette collections, which turned into CD collections, which moved to iTunes mp3 playlists and now a curated streaming collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ thoughts on zoom</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/thoughts-on-zoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/thoughts-on-zoom/</guid>
      <description>The past few months have placed immense demand on remote working and particularly video-conferencing tools. This has placed greater scrutiny on the security practices of companies like Zoom which has received a great deal of press - resulting in better transparency and a commitment to its users for improving its controls.
Putting opinions and conjecture aside for a moment, Zoom&amp;rsquo;s current posture and response got me thinking - in particular, the following aspects were of interest to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ init</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/init/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/init/</guid>
      <description>A new tech blog sees the light of day. As if there weren’t enough of them already&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/training/</guid>
      <description>Super-NetOps The following presentations are a part of training days given to F5 Networks customers and partners on automation and orchestration. Lab guides accompanying the presentation can be found here: https://clouddocs.f5.com/training/community/programmability/html/intro.html
Author: F5 Networks
Presenter: Shain Singh
  Introduction to Automation and Orchestration   DevOps Methodology and Infrastructure as Code   Security in a DevOps Environment   Additional Notes for Lab Guide   DevSecOps Presentation given to F5 Networks partners as part of a Security workshop (including a Capture The Flag tournament).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/about/</guid>
      <description>$ POST /about?definition=blog पुरुषार्थ (puruṣārtha)- the Hindu belief that there are four goals or objectives for human existence.
 Kāma: sensory pleasure Artha: material prosperity Dharma: moral righteousness Mokṣa: spiritual liberation  My aim will be to cover materials painted in the colours of the four goals of puruṣārtha.
Enjoy your visit.
नमस्ते (Namaste)
$ GET /info?id=shsingh  Bio I know stuff about things, or things about stuff&amp;hellip; At least I try to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ research</title>
      <link>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oi.shain.io/thoughts/research/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe&amp;quot; - Abraham Lincoln I am still learning how exactly to use this medium to write. The lack of content for a while is not indicative of an absence of posts to publish, rather a “getting to know one’s surrounds”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>